we all tired a little bit so I arrived
我们都有点累所以我到了
here two days ago 27 hours flight from
两天前从这里起飞27小时
Australia about now is the time is 11:45
澳大利亚大约现在的时间是11:45
p.m. so it's it's a bit it's about two
pm大概是两个
hours after my normal bedtime so
我正常就寝时间之后的几个小时
hopefully my presentation will be it's
希望我的演讲会是
just interesting because if it's not I'm
只是很有趣，因为如果不是，我就是
gonna be the first person fallen asleep
成为第一个睡着的人
so this presentation is called streaming
所以这个演讲叫做流媒体
to Anu Jakarta AE so why has why have I
去Anu Jakarta AE，为什么会有我
my name's James Roper by the way why
我叫詹姆斯·罗珀（James Roper）
have I come all the way from the other
我一路走来吗
side of the world to talk to you so I'm
世界的一面与你交谈，所以我
gonna cook eclipse kamila I am the lead
我要煮日食卡米尔
of the micro profile
微观轮廓
reactive project I work for a company
我在一家公司工作的被动项目
called light Bend anybody here heard of
叫光弯曲这里的任何人都听说过
light Bend a few so light Bend is the
轻弯一些，所以轻弯是
company behind occur play framework
背后的公司发生发挥框架
logon and the Scala programming language
登录和Scala编程语言
we also were founding in or created the
我们也是在
reactive manifesto founding members of
反应性宣言的创始成员
the reactive streams initiative and
反应流倡议和
pretty much anything reactive usually
通常几乎没有任何反应
lightened has its fingers in it
减轻了它的手指
somewhere
某处
so my role I'm the senior developer in
所以我的角色是
the light Bend office of the CTO office
CTO办公室的光弯办公室
of the CTO is a kind of weird team in
CTO的团队是
different companies basically it means
基本上不同的公司意味着
the CTO has a crazy idea and I have to
CTO有一个疯狂的主意，我必须
go and make it kind of happen I
去让它发生我
co-created logon so logon is like Ben's
共同创建的登录，因此登录就像Ben的
reactive - services framework and I used
反应性-服务框架，我用
to be the tech lead of pride about the
成为骄傲的技术领导
tech late of play framework which is a
技术后期播放框架
high productivity reactive web
高生产率反应网
development framework prior to that I
我之前的开发框架
worked for a about set there's any
为设置而工作
Germans in the room probably snickering
房间里的德国人可能在窃笑
it was a it was a a social network I
这是一个社交网络，我
joined at its pay
有偿加入
and then it started going downhill so I
然后开始下坡，所以我
need I probably want to move to back to
需要我可能想回到
Germany someday would be cool so any
有一天德国会很酷，所以任何
startups want me to destroy their
创业公司要我摧毁他们的
company let me know and I worked for
公司让我知道，我曾在
Atlassian before that and I used to use
Atlassian之前，我曾经使用
I cut my teeth in in my career on j2ee
我在j2ee上的职业生涯很坚定
1.4 actually haven't used Java AE in
1.4实际上并没有使用Java AE
anger since like a jibe a 2.1 and some
愤怒，因为像吉布2.1和一些
of those lovely things so what are we
那些可爱的东西，那么我们是什么
going to look at today
今天要看
the first thing we're going to look at
我们要看的第一件事
is why we need streaming this is the
这就是为什么我们需要流媒体，这就是
first part of this talk is very
演讲的第一部分非常
architectural not actually related to to
与建筑无关
really Jakarta a a micro profile or
真正的雅加达aa微型个人资料或
anything like that
像那样的东西
will will contrast monoliths to
将对比整体
microfiber tsa's we'll see what the
超细纤维tsa，我们将看到
differences are what the constraint
差异是什么约束
differences in constraints are and the
约束条件的差异是和
technical challenges when we take the
我们采取的技术挑战
traditional approaches that we used in
我们使用的传统方法
monoliths that that we have when we try
我们尝试时拥有的整体
to apply them to monoliths to micro
将它们应用于整体式微
services and we'll look at how streaming
服务，我们将看一下如何流式传输
can solve some of these problems we'll
可以解决其中一些问题，我们将
also have a demo and in the demo we'll
也有一个演示，在演示中，我们将
take a look at some in development specs
看看一些开发规范
for Mac profile we'll take a look at
对于Mac个人资料，我们将介绍一下
some ideas for possible future specs and
一些可能的未来规格的想法，以及
we will see streaming in action
我们将看到流媒体的运行
so monoliths have allowed us to take
所以巨石让我们可以
consistency for granted you can think of
您可以想到的一致性
it like oxygen okay so when I go say
就像氧气还可以，所以当我说
from home to work I don't need to it's
从家里上班我不需要
incredibly important that I always have
我一直都非常重要
oxygen to breathe because otherwise I'll
呼吸氧气，否则我会
die but I don't think okay where am I
死了，但我不认为我在哪里
gonna get my oxygen from when I get to
当我到达时会得到氧气
work how am I gonna breathe on the way
工作我该如何呼吸
to work I don't think I just take it for
工作我不认为我只是为了
granted it's incredibly important but I
当然，这很重要，但我
take it for granted and consistency is
理所当然，一致性是
somewhat the same in monoliths we we
整体中有些相同，我们
take it for granted we don't even
认为这是理所当然的，我们什至没有
realize how important it is for us
意识到这对我们很重要
because it's incredibly important very
因为它非常重要
few business applications are able to
很少有业务应用程序能够
cope with with inconsistent stage weave
应对不一致的舞台编织
so for example an order service saying
例如订单服务说
that this order is submitted and the
该订单已提交，并且
payment service saying this order
付款服务说这笔订单
doesn't exist because then you don't get
不存在，因为那样你就不会得到
paid for the order okay it consistency
支付订单，可以保持一致性
is incredibly important but monoliths
是非常重要的，但独树一帜
have allowed us to take it for granted
让我们认为这是理所当然的
so it turns out when you have a single
所以事实证明，当你只有一个
database the world is very easy and the
数据库世界非常容易，
reason for this is that we can use
原因是我们可以使用
transactions we can use asset
我们可以使用资产的交易
transactions all of our operations can
交易我们所有的业务都可以
be done inside a transaction and
在交易内完成
transactions do this by giving us this
交易通过给我们这个来做到这一点
illusion of a single consistent current
单一持续电流的错觉
state there is a concept of what is the
国家有一个概念是什么
state of the system now okay what can I
现在系统状态还可以，我该怎么办
do now what does it look like now what
现在就做什么现在看起来像什么
what and and that that idea of now is
现在的想法是什么
all consistent you're not going to go to
所有一致的你不会去
the the order table and say that the the
订单表，并说
order is in the awaiting payment status
订单处于等待付款状态
and the payment tables to say that it
和付款表说
doesn't exist you have this consistent
不存在，你有这个一致
state of now and it all is consistent so
现在的状态，一切都是一致的
we can think about data as being a
我们可以将数据视为
static thing it's sitting there at rest
静态的东西坐在那里休息
it's waiting for our operation to come
等待我们的手术来
in we do our operation and then we
在我们进行操作，然后我们
commit and we go away it's it's just
承诺，我们走了，就是这样
there nicely for us value is handled for
对我们来说，很有价值
us so the transactions ensure that our
我们这样的交易确保了我们
operations are atomic we can't have
我们无法拥有原子操作
partial updates if I update one table
如果我更新一个表，则进行部分更新
and
和
another table and that fails the update
另一个表，更新失败
to the first table will be rolled back
到第一个表将被回滚
he can't either the entire operation
他无法完成整个手术
succeeds or it gets rolled back and
成功或它被回滚并
consistency is also enforced so if my
一致性也会得到加强，因此如果我的
payment table references a an order that
付款表引用的订单
the the database is able to guarantee
数据库能够保证
that that order exists in that order
该订单存在于该订单中
table via foreign key constraints
通过外键约束表
concurrency is also handled for us so
并发也为我们处理
among other things that means that
除其他外，这意味着
there's no uncommitted reads you say you
没有没有承诺的读你说你
can't have something coming in and
不能有东西进来
unseen data but then later gets well
看不见的数据，但后来恢复良好
back so if we were to visualize what
回来，所以如果我们要想像什么
this looks like we can imagine that
看起来我们可以想象
we've got a database and in there are
我们有一个数据库，里面有
some tables and the transaction might
一些表，交易可能
come in and it says I want to do an
进来，它说我想做一个
operation on your tables to the database
对表进行数据库操作
and what the database does is it it's as
数据库的作用是
if it materializes this view and says
如果实现了这种观点并说
okay here's my tables they're yours to
好吧，这是我的桌子，它们是你的
work with you can do whatever you want
与您合作可以做任何您想做的事
with them you don't have to worry about
与他们在一起，您不必担心
when anyone else is doing these are
当别人做这些的时候
yours too your tables and yours alone to
您的餐桌也一个人
do whatever you want another transaction
做你想做的另一笔交易
might come in and it does the same thing
可能会进来，它做同样的事情
to that transaction here your tables you
在这里进行交易
can do whatever you want they yours and
可以做任何你想做的事
yours alone to work with you don't need
不需要你一个人与你一起工作
to worry about what any other
担心什么
transactions are doing and so when those
交易正在做，所以当那些
transactions both commit the database
事务都提交数据库
it's through its magic through and they
通过它的魔力，他们
say see through through rather through
说透通
locks and various things ensures that
锁和各种事物确保
those two updated states end up being
那两个更新的状态最终被
merged into the database in a way that
以某种方式合并到数据库中
makes sense and that maintains
有道理，并保持
consistency
一致性
when we move to cloud native market
当我们转向云原生市场时
services
服务
I can't view of the world this
我看不到这个世界
consistent view of the world
一致的世界观
it breaks down okay our oxygen
可以分解我们的氧气
disappears we can no longer take
消失了，我们不能再忍受了
consistencies Gravatt and so the problem
一致性Gravatt等问题
is that that you know in when you use
是您在使用时知道的
micro services each micro service should
微服务每个微服务应
have its own database its own State
有自己的数据库，自己的状态
there was a article published by thought
有一篇思想发表的文章
works recently on basics basically said
最近基本的作品基本上说
if you're sharing or a database between
如果您是共享或数据库之间
all your services you don't have any
您没有的所有服务
decoupling between services you don't
您不需要的服务之间的脱钩
you've just got a more complex
你只是更复杂
deployment you don't have micro services
没有微服务的部署
micro services means that h service has
微服务意味着h服务具有
its own database so you've got multiple
它自己的数据库，所以您有多个
databases and this makes the world hard
数据库，这使世界变得艰难
because you've got multiples databases
因为你有多个数据库
you now have many states now within each
您现在在每个状态中都有许多状态
database you can have an asset
您可以拥有资产的数据库
transaction something that's consistent
交易一致的东西
but you have multiple version of these
但是你有这些的多个版本
you can't have one consistent current
你不可能有一个一致的电流
view of the world
世界观
so each different service with its own
所以每个不同的服务都有自己的
database has its own idea of what the
数据库对什么有自己的想法
current state is and they don't all
目前的状态是，他们还不是全部
match because they can't because
匹配，因为他们不能，因为
transactions can't spend services and so
交易不能花费服务，因此
we can't think of our current state as
我们不能认为我们目前的状态是
being this thing that's in rest waiting
一直在等待的东西
for us to make a request and all we have
让我们提出要求，我们拥有的一切
to to acknowledge the the moving nature
承认运动的本质
of the system a data is we've got some
系统的数据是我们有一些
data in the database but there are
数据库中的数据，但有
currently other things happening in
目前正在发生其他事情
motion we've got to think of our
运动，我们必须想到我们的
database a data has been in motion
数据库中的数据一直在移动
failure is not handled for us okay if I
如果我们不能解决失败的话
do an update on on service one if I tell
如果我告诉我，请更新一下服务
it to do an update and then it's part of
它进行更新，然后它是
my business operation I need to then
我的业务需要
tell service two to update if the
告诉服务二更新
service - if that fails for some reason
服务-如果由于某种原因失败
maybe there's a network outage whatever
也许有网络中断
then that's not going to succeed but
那不会成功，但是
you've still got the update that
你仍然有更新
happened on service one so what do you
发生在服务一，那么你怎么办
do do you roll it back what if you crash
你会回滚吗？
yourself and there's no enforcement of
你自己，没有强制执行
consistency if you've got two different
如果您有两个不同，则保持一致
databases you can't have a foreign key
您没有外键的数据库
constraint from one database to the
从一个数据库到
other it doesn't work that way
其他它不是那样的
and concurrency is inherent in this
并发是固有的
system so when an operation comes in and
系统，以便在进行操作时
does an update here it then takes time
在这里进行更新，这需要时间
for that to propagate here and time for
为了在这里传播和时间
proper to propagate things it's with
适当传播它的东西
where we had atomic operations where it
我们在哪里进行原子操作
was like a CH operation happened
就像发生了CH手术
instantly in a monolith we now have
立刻变成了整体，我们现在有了
operations taking time to propagate
需要花费时间进行传播的操作
through our system
通过我们的系统
so this is what it might look like if
所以这可能是什么样子
were to visualize it we've got all our
可视化它，我们拥有了所有
services and an operation comes into and
服务和操作进入
is handled by service a and another
由服务a和另一个处理
operation comes in it's handled by
操作由它来处理
service F and these trigger operations
服务F和这些触发操作
and updates on other services B and a
以及其他服务B和a的更新
got updated and then we've actually got
得到更新，然后我们实际上得到了
an out-of-order operation so he was he
乱序的操作，所以他是他
was updated first by the second one and
由第二个第一次更新
B was updated first by the first one and
B由第一个先更新，然后
then they reversed and do the other
然后他们扭转了，做另一个
things so now how those operations still
所以现在这些操作如何
valid because the state's changed what
有效，因为国家改变了什么
happens if we did this operation and G&amp;G
如果我们执行此操作和G＆G会发生
crashes maybe it's I'm unable to handle
崩溃也许是我无法处理
the operation because it's database goes
操作，因为它是数据库
down or there's runs out of memory
出现故障或内存不足
network goes down what does that mean
网络中断意味着什么
for the operate for the updates that
用于更新的操作
we've already done in all these other
我们已经在所有其他方面做了
services I mean should they be rolled
服务，我的意思是应该滚动
back should we retype try on J whose
返回我们应该重新输入尝试J
responsibility is that to make sure that
责任是确保
that happens maybe we say well I
发生这种情况，也许我们说得好
received the request first it's its
首先收到了请求，这是它的
responsibility to coordinate everything
协调一切的责任
okay but the thing that felt failures
好的，但是感觉失败的东西
often don't happen in isolation you have
通常不会孤立地发生
you know data centers with racks of
您知道带有机架的数据中心
servers and often like a whole rack will
服务器，通常像整个机架一样
go down due to a network problem or
由于网络问题而掉线或
power problem and what if ing were on
电源问题，如果开机
the same rack so now our coordinators
相同的机架，所以现在我们的协调员
gone what what do the rest of the
剩下的什么了
services do now do they even know that
服务现在做，他们甚至知道
something's gone wrong and of course the
出了点问题，当然
second operation here has already done
这里的第二项操作已经完成
updates depending on updates that the
更新取决于
first one has done what does that mean
第一个做了什么意思
for the its updates maybe they're now
对于它的更新，也许他们现在
invalid so the whole the integrity of
无效所以整个的完整性
and consistency of our whole system is
整个系统的一致性是
now called into question
现在受到质疑
what worked when we used my monoliths
当我们用我的巨石时，什么起作用了
will not work in cloud native
将无法在本机云中工作
micro-services okay we cannot rely on
微服务好吧，我们不能依靠
consistency in the same way that we and
一致性，就像我们和
we cannot take consistency for granted
我们不能认为一致性是理所当然的
so think examples of things that do work
所以想一些可行的事例
in monoliths crud works okay because
在整体堆中工作正常，因为
crud depends on a single to consistent
关键取决于单一或一致
state you do an update here do an update
声明您在这里进行更新
there and they can be dependent on each
在那里，他们可以依靠每个
other and but because you've got the
其他，但因为你有
database minute managing that it makes
数据库分钟管理
sure that it's fine and we it does that
确保一切正常，我们做到了
through the relying on transactions so
通过依赖交易所以
where you can rely on transactions to
您可以依靠交易来
clean up after ourselves and make things
自己清理并制造东西
consistent but that depends on the
一致，但这取决于
single database and for all this we can
单个数据库，为此，我们可以
do rest and rest works in in monoliths
在整体中休息和休息
because the data because we have this
因为数据，因为我们有这个
single database it can handle manage the
它可以处理的单个数据库
failure like a wrist has nothing in
像手腕一样的失败根本没有
built to manage failure you view if the
专为管理故障而设计，您可以查看
rest request fails there's nothing's
休息请求失败，没有任何东西
going to retry it for you now things go
现在要为您重试
that's going to try and roll it back for
这将尝试将其回滚
you but that's okay when you have a
你，但是当你有一个
single database because the database can
单个数据库，因为该数据库可以
manage that for you
为你管理
when we move to cloud native micro
当我们迁移到云原生微
services we need a different approach
服务我们需要不同的方法
and so events is an answer to this
因此，事件就是对此的答案
problem
问题
events convey facts okay so if I were to
事件可以传达事实，所以如果我愿意
say that this order is currently
说这个订单目前
submitted okay that's not a fact or if I
提交了，这不是事实，还是我
say that this order is in the submitted
说此订单已提交
State that's not a fact why is that not
声明这不是事实，为什么不是
a fact because while I said that
一个事实是因为虽然我说
something could have come and canceled
可能有东西来取消了
it and it could be wrong I don't know
它，这可能是错误的，我不知道
for sure that it's currently that
可以肯定的是
because this these services are
因为这些服务是
independent
独立
okay so current state is not a fact what
好吧，所以目前的状态不是事实
is fact is events that happened in the
事实是发生在
past so for example the user submitted
过去，例如，用户提交了
the hora that's a fact when the user
当用户使用时的事实
submits the order it's a fact that they
提交订单是事实，他们
do about that can never be invalidated
做到这一点永远不会失效
even if they go and cancel it well that
即使他们去取消它
doesn't change the fact that they
并没有改变他们
submitted it
提交了
in fact they can't cancel it if they
实际上，如果他们
didn't submit it at first so that
一开始没有提交
submitted fact always remains true and
提交的事实始终保持真实，
so if I receive an event I can guarantee
因此，如果我收到一个活动，我可以保证
I can rely on that I can rely that
我可以依靠我可以依靠
that's true I like like in a monolith I
的确，我喜欢独角兽
could rely on my current state if I
如果我可以依靠我目前的状态
receive an event I can I can rely that
收到一个事件我可以依靠
that fact is true we also need so if we
这个事实是真的，我们也需要，如果我们
then embrace events we need some way to
然后拥抱事件，我们需要某种方式
get these events around our system and
在我们的系统中获取这些事件，并
to do that we need at least ones
为此，我们至少需要一个
messaging so if we can ensure that when
消息传递，因此我们可以确保何时
an event happens that we have a
一个事件发生，我们有一个
guarantee that that this event will be
确保该事件将
propagated to everything that depends on
传播到一切取决于
it at least once then we can ensure that
它至少一次，那么我们可以确保
our system will eventually converge on
我们的系统最终将收敛于
on what the current state is that that
目前的状态是
our services can agree that the order is
我们的服务可以同意订单是
submitted or order is canceled and so to
提交或订单被取消等
bring this all together what we need to
将所有这些整合在一起
do is take a stream centric view we
要做的是以河流为中心
don't want to just have events just then
不想只是在那时有事件
it doesn't work to just kind of
它不只是一种
magically fire events everywhere we need
在我们需要的任何地方神奇地触发事件
to to control them so we need to take to
去控制他们，所以我们需要采取
consider our data rather than thinking
考虑我们的数据而不是思考
of our source of truth our data what we
我们的真理来源我们的数据
what were what our system state is Ben
我们的系统状态是什么Ben
that current state we need to think of
我们需要考虑的当前状态
it our data has been the events so if
它是我们的数据是事件，所以如果
you have all the events you know what
你拥有所有的事件，你知道什么
the data you best the data of the system
您最好的数据系统的数据
that's the state of the system some of
那是系统的状态
these events may be in rest they may be
这些事件可能处于静止状态
stored in a database but some of them
存储在数据库中，但其中一些
might be currently being propagated
可能当前正在传播
through the system some of them are in
通过系统中的一些
motion
运动
and so we we have no single state we
所以我们没有单一的状态
don't have this we don't no longer need
没有这个，我们不再需要
to rely on transactions because we've
依靠交易，因为我们已经
got we're not taking a single state view
我们没有采取单一状态视图
of the world we're just taking an event
我们只是在参加一个活动
view where we can rely on the facts that
查看我们可以依靠的事实
we've received and because of this that
我们已经收到，因此
the single state of the system is is
系统的单一状态是
more a state of constantly converging so
更处于不断收敛的状态
rather than thinking in terms of this is
而不是这样思考
what my current state is our system is
我当前的状态是我们的系统是
is moving towards convergence
正在走向融合
propagating if I mean if if you
传播如果我的意思是如果你
disconnected all the inputs from the
断开所有输入与
system if everybody stopped using the
系统，如果每个人都停止使用
system then sure it will converge and
系统，然后确保它将收敛，
all the services will agree on what
所有的服务都会就什么达成共识
their current state is but as long as
他们目前的状态是
there's people using it there's new
有人在用它
inputs coming in new events coming in
输入新事件
events being propagated events in motion
事件正在传播中
a system will be in this state of
系统将处于这种状态
constantly converging never quite
不断收敛从未完全
getting there but always on the way
到达那里，但总是在路上
there and to do this we need to control
在那里，要做到这一点，我们需要控制
it and we do this by using streams
它，我们通过使用流来做到这一点
within our events down streams and these
在我们事件的下游
streams allow us to propagate these our
流让我们传播这些
data throughout the system so we could
整个系统中的数据，因此我们可以
visualize this we've got service a and B
想象一下，我们有服务a和B
and we put a stream between them so a
我们在他们之间放了一条小溪
stream is a pipe now service a does
流是一个管道，现在服务一个
something and it emits an event and it
东西，它发出一个事件，它
puts it into the pipe into the stream
将其放入管道中
and it does something else in this event
它在此事件中还有其他作用
and it puts it into the stream and these
并将其放入流中，这些
events are now on their way to to
事件正在向
service B and possibly other services so
服务B和其他可能的服务
it can it can fan out to multiple
它可以扇出多个
services that depend on these events but
取决于这些事件的服务，但
what happens if service B at the time
如果当时服务B会发生什么
that service a emits these events has
发出这些事件的服务有
crashed because we're using that waste
崩溃了，因为我们正在使用这些废物
once and at least once mechanism to get
至少一次获得机制
them from service to service B service a
他们从服务到服务B服务a
doesn't need to worry once its emitted
发射后无需担心
the event it's out of the picture it
如果它不在画面中
doesn't need to retry it doesn't need to
不需要重试，不需要
write rollback it knows that it's
写回滚，它知道这是
emitted the events sent sent this fact
发出发送事件发送此事实
this is a fact that this has happened
这是事实
and it can it's completely out of the
它可以完全脱离
picture
图片
servus bathing can then you know be
servus洗澡可以吗？
fixed and come back online and so at
修复后重新在线等
some point and once it's done that it
一点，一旦完成就可以了
can start reprocessing those events and
可以开始重新处理这些事件并
come to conversions
进行转化
so this is the most important thing that
所以这是最重要的
I want people to get from this
我希望人们从中得到好处
presentation if we model the system
系统建模的演示
using streams we embrace events we no
使用流我们拥抱事件我们没有
longer need a single state we don't need
不再需要一个我们不需要的状态
transactions we don't need to have this
交易我们不需要这个
current state view of the world and so
当前的世界观等等
we can take eventual consistency for
我们可以采取最终的一致性
granted so when we moved from monoliths
当我们脱离巨石时，这是理所当然的
to micro services we lost the ability to
微服务，我们失去了
take a consistency for granted but
认为一致性是理所当然的，但是
streams gives us gives us us back back
溪流给了我们，使我们回到了我们
allowing us once again to take
让我们再次采取
consistency for granted and what that
理所当然的一致性以及那
means in practice as a developer you no
在实践中意味着您没有
longer you don't need to worry about
时间更长，您无需担心
failure you don't need to worry at a
失败，您无需担心
handling fail you don't need to worry
处理失败，您无需担心
about handling consistency you just need
关于处理您只需要的一致性
to worry about your business concerns
担心您的业务问题
which is what you meant to worry about
这就是你要担心的
as a as a developer and the
作为开发者和
architectural approach that you've taken
您采用的架构方法
we'll worry about consistency for you so
我们会担心您的一致性，所以
what does this have to do with Jakarta
这和雅加达有什么关系
AAA
AAA级
currently JMS and MD B's are the best of
目前，JMS和MD B是最好的
Jakarta AE has to offer and while all
雅加达AE必须提供，而所有
these things can be achieved using them
这些事情可以通过使用它们来实现
they are rather heavy weight mg bees
他们是很重的毫克蜜蜂
require a lot of kind of code around
需要很多种代码
them they were design for a time where
他们他们设计了一段时间
you had multiple marks so you had a
你有多个标记，所以你有一个
monolith here and a monolith there and
这里的巨石和那里的巨石
you had a very heavy weight so this
你体重很重所以这个
might be maintained by a business unit
可能由业务部门维护
of a very large business unit and this
一个非常大的业务部门
one by another very large business unit
一个又一个非常大的业务部门
and conceptually you had a very heavy
从概念上讲，
weight transfer of now this process is
现在这个过程的重量转移是
going to be handled by this system over
将由该系统处理
here to do that whereas when you move to
在这里这样做而当您移至
streams with microservices you know have
您知道的具有微服务的流
a single operation will will consist of
一个操作将包括
many events potentially tens 20 hundred
许多事件可能数万
events all going through all going
一切都在进行
through many different services and so
通过许多不同的服务等等
you need something that's much lighter
您需要的东西要轻得多
weight than what's previously offered so
重量比以前提供的要重
there are new efforts in micro profile
微观方面有新的努力
to change this so the first thing that
改变这一点，所以第一件事
we've done is we've created an approach
我们已经完成了，我们已经创建了一种方法
to reactive document that that guides
指导的反应性文件
adoption of reactive features so when I
采用反应性功能，所以当我
talk about streaming and and maintaining
谈论流媒体和维护
consistency I'm really talking about
我在说的一致性
reactive principles that allow you to to
反应性原则，使您能够
build systems that are highly decoupled
建立高度解耦的系统
and this reactive document is going to
这个反应性文件将
help guide the creation of future specs
帮助指导将来规格的创建
and updating of this existing specs the
并更新此现有规格
micro profile reactive project has been
微型配置文件反应项目已经
started and this has two sub
开始，这有两个子
specifications the first is a strength
规格第一是实力
project for manipulating streams so when
用于操纵流的项目，因此何时
I want to do have a stream of data and I
我想拥有一个数据流，我
want to do an operation on a map or
想要在地图上进行操作或
store something to a database or filter
将内容存储到数据库或过滤器
this library gutter does that and then
这个库装订线会这样做，然后
then the other sub project is a
那么另一个子项目是
specification for asynchronous
异步规范
communication called reactive messaging
通信称为反应式消息传递
and so this is about communicating
所以这是关于交流
between services and getting events from
在服务和获取事件之间
one service to another there's also some
一种服务到另一种，还有一些
future possibilities and there's been a
未来的可能性，并且有一个
lot of discussion on the micro profile
关于微观概况的大量讨论
mailing list just in the past few weeks
过去几周的邮件列表
about this event sourced entity support
关于此事件来源实体的支持
so actually rather than storing your
所以实际上而不是存储您的
your data in tables storing the events
您的数据存储在存储事件的表中
and then computing the state from the
然后从
events and publishing entity streams so
事件和发布实体流如此
CQRS where you separate the the separate
CQRS，您在其中分开
your your read side model that the
您的阅读侧模型
entities the things that that are able
实体能够做的事情
to validate and produce new events from
验证并产生新事件
the things that then go and query them
然后去查询的东西
and tell what the current state is
并告知当前状态
so now we're going to move on to the
所以现在我们将继续
demo now the demo is I'm going to show a
演示现在，演示是我要展示的
sample app called online auction it's
示例应用程序称为在线拍卖
it's an eBay clone it's not quite up to
这是eBay的克隆，还不够
competing with eBay but it will get
与eBay竞争，但它将获得
there someday
有一天
none of these specs that I've just
这些规范我都没有
talked about actually exist yet okay so
谈到实际上存在但还可以
I can't run a Java AE server and
我无法运行Java AE服务器，并且
demonstrated to you because the the
向您展示，因为
specs don't exist but as I said on the
规格不存在，但正如我在
co-creator of logon and logon implements
登录和登录工具的共同创建者
these these principles and so I've gone
这些这些原则，所以我走了
and implemented the specs in the current
并在当前实施了规范
form very early everything could change
形成很早，一切都会改变
but in their current form have
但以目前的形式
implemented them on top of logon and
在登录之上实施它们，并
then I've ported this online auction
那么我已经移植了这个在线拍卖
demo app which actually exists as a demo
实际作为演示存在的演示应用
app for lots of other things to use
该应用程序还有很多其他用途
these new specs so here's our online
这些新规格，所以这是我们的在线
auction app it's it's very pretty
拍卖应用程序，它非常漂亮
I can create an item I'm logged in as
我可以创建一个我登录时使用的项目
Mary at the moment so Mary is going to
此刻的玛丽，所以玛丽要
sell her bike it's it's a red bike we're
卖她的自行车，这是一辆红色的自行车
in Europe so let's use euros and ten
在欧洲，所以我们用欧元和十
seconds probably too short for this
秒可能太短了
auction and go ten hours so create it
拍卖并花10个小时创建它
and once I'm happy with it
而一旦我对此感到满意
I'll start the auction
我开始拍卖
now logging is someone else very secure
现在记录是别人非常安全的
you just select your user from a
您只需从
drop-down and I'm going to search for
下拉菜单，我将要搜索
that item so I'm logged in as John now
该项目，所以我现在以John身份登录
and I'll search and I can see there it
我会搜索，然后在那里看到
is my bike can't propose that current
是我的自行车不能提出建议
price and so I can click on it and I can
价格，所以我可以点击它，我可以
place a bid I'll be 10 euros
出价我将是10欧元
and like eBay the minimum price was 50
像eBay一样，最低价格是50
says the 50 cents you don't actually bid
说你实际上没有出价的50美分
the current price it automatically
当前价格自动
increments for you as other people bid
随着其他人竞价，您的收入会增加
against you so if I log in as as myself
反对你，所以如果我以我自己的身份登录
and I place a bid of 5 heroes we see
我出价5个英雄
that's been accepted except that it's
被接受，除了
automatically outbid by John because his
约翰自动出价高于
maximum bid was 10 euros so I'll place a
最高出价是10欧元，所以我将
bit of 20 euros and that's been accepted
20欧元的一点，这已经被接受
50 cents more than John's high-speeds so
比约翰的高速多了50美分
the current price is 10 euros 50 so if
当前的价格是10欧元50所以如果
we go and search for the black again we
我们去寻找黑色再次
can see here there's the black and we
可以看到这里有黑色，我们
saw before that the current price is 10
之前看到的当前价格是10
euros 50 but it's not showing any
50欧元，但未显示任何
current price here there must be a
当前价格这里一定有一个
problem so let's go and have a look at
问题，让我们去看看
the code
编码
so this is you know we we have a number
所以这是你知道我们有一个号码
of services one service is an item
服务一项是一项
service that's where that was
服务就是那个地方
that's what handles creating the item
这就是创建项目的处理方式
and describing the item now the service
并描述该项目现在服务
is the bid service
是出价服务
it handles accepting bids and managing
它负责接受投标和管理
the auction and another service is the
拍卖和另一项服务是
search service and it handles
搜索服务及其处理
maintaining search index of all events
维护所有事件的搜索索引
and the search service does that by
搜索服务通过
subscribing to a topic of by subscribing
通过订阅订阅主题
to the events coming from the item and
来自该项目的事件和
the bid service so since the price isn't
出价服务，因为价格不是
been updated in the search service there
在那里的搜索服务中已更新
must be a problem with the bid events
一定是出价事件的问题
that about that are supposed to be
关于那应该是
reaching there from the bid service here
从此处的出价服务到达那里
is where those services can subscribe to
这些服务可以订阅的地方
their bid events so we can see here this
他们的竞标活动，所以我们可以在这里看到
is an application scoped beam and c-d-i
是应用范围的梁和CDI
and we can see this incoming annotation
我们可以看到这个传入的注释
so this is part of the messaging spec
所以这是消息传递规范的一部分
and it's saying the topic is the the BD
就是说主题是BD
events and it gets the bit event and it
事件，它得到位事件，它
does convert to a document it then
确实将其转换为文档
assists it it's asynchronous so it's
帮助它是异步的，所以它是
using a completion stage to represent
使用完成阶段来表示
the result and their returns that that
结果和他们的回报
result now here because the completion
现在结果在这里，因为完成
stage because this code looks almost
阶段，因为这段代码看起来几乎
identical to the code handling item
与代码处理项目相同
events and we know that the item events
事件，我们知道项目事件
again there because the bike does come
再次在那里，因为自行车确实来了
up in the search index - - in the first
在搜索索引中-在第一个中
place it's just the price that's not
只是价格不是
been updated it's probably not in the
已更新，可能不在
search service that the problem is so
搜索服务，问题是如此
let's go and have a look at our bidding
我们去看看我们的出价
service where the events are being
事件发生的服务
published so you can see I have this
发表，所以你可以看到我有这个
method here called publish event log and
这里的方法称为发布事件日志，
in this case it's not taking a parameter
在这种情况下，它没有参数
rather it's returning a processor which
而是要返回一个处理器
is a reactive streams thing are active
是反应性流事物是活跃的
streams it has it has an input and an
它有一个输入和一个流
output and the input is action events
输出，输入是动作事件
and the output is bit events now auction
现在输出的是位事件
events the bidding service here is using
此处的出价服务正在使用的事件
event sourcing so with event sourcing
事件源，这样事件源
rather than it is so persisting
而不是那么持久
what the current did what the current
当前做什么？
winning is and what that what their bid
获胜是什么，他们的出价是什么
is you just persist all the events so
你只是坚持所有的事情，所以
this person placed this bid this person
这个人把这个人出价
place that bid this person plays this
此人出价的地方
other bid and then whenever you need to
其他出价，然后在需要时
look at what the current price is you
看看你现在的价格是多少
simply load all those events replay them
只需加载所有这些事件即可重播它们
to get your current state and so because
得到你的当前状态，所以因为
we are storing these in an event log we
我们将这些存储在事件日志中
can consume them as a stream of auction
可以将它们作为拍卖流消费
events and so this is we then use this
事件，所以这是我们然后使用此
is the the reactive strength micro
是无功强度微
profile reactive stream spec for
的配置式反应流规范
manipulating these events we create a
处理这些事件，我们创建了一个
builder that's going to take the auction
将要拍卖的建筑商
events as an input we filter them
事件作为输入，我们对其进行过滤
because not all the events that we
因为不是我们所有的事件
persist in our own database we
坚持在我们自己的数据库中
necessarily want to publish to the to
一定要发布到
the world we are mean in this case were
在这种情况下，我们的意思是
publishing bit biased and being finished
发布位偏见并完成
events and then we convert them to an
事件，然后将它们转换为
outside representation of the events so
事件的外部表示
just as you wouldn't return your JPA
就像您不会退还您的JPA
entities directly from a rest service
直接来自休息服务的实体
you've converted into some other object
您已经转换为其他对象
that that represents your external API
代表您的外部API
we're doing the same thing here we're
我们在这里做同样的事情
converting our internally persisted
转换我们内部持久的
events to so something that semantically
事件发生在语义上
represents the same thing but that looks
代表同一件事，但看起来
that is is more suitable for a public
那更适合公众
API now you may have noticed there's no
API，现在您可能已经注意到没有
annotations on this and that's actually
对此的注释实际上
the problem here so let's add them this
这里的问题，所以让我们添加他们
this publisher is going to take as its
这个发布者将以
input as its incoming stream the event
输入事件作为其传入流
log so that those oxygen events it's
记录这些氧气事件
going to read them from the event log
要从事件日志中读取它们
and then it's going be up going so the
然后它会上升，所以
the things that the processor converts
处理器转换的东西
them to is going to be published to
他们将被发布到
Kafka and so that bidding event topic
卡夫卡等竞标活动主题
so now once that saved logon supports
所以现在一旦保存的登录支持
hot reloads so I don't need to do
热装，所以我不需要做
anything I just need to save it and it
我需要保存的所有内容
should be reloaded now when I search
搜索时应该立即重新加载
here the first thing that I'm probably
这是我可能要做的第一件事
going to have to do is a database based
要做的是基于数据库
migration because I forgot to have those
迁移是因为我忘了拥有那些
annotations there before and so of
之前的注释等等
course my search service is in the wrong
当然我的搜索服务有误
state all the future things of course
陈述所有未来的事情
that's going to work but the stuff then
那将起作用，但随后的东西
is this in the past because I had this
过去是因为我有这个
bug there before I'm gonna have to fix
我必须修复之前的错误
that up right there's no way that the
那个就没有办法
current price could be shown there when
当前价格可以在此处显示
I hit search going that's just not
我击中搜索，那不是
possible
可能
well yes it is you see what's happened
好吧，是的，你看到发生了什么事
here is because of your streaming I've
这是因为我的流媒体
got this property in my system now that
现在在我的系统中获得了该属性
it can self heal
它可以自我修复
of course the actual bog where where the
当然实际沼泽在哪里
annotations were in person that the
注释是亲自面对的
system's not gonna fix that itself but
系统无法自行修复，但
once I fixed that bug the actual data
一旦我修复了该错误的实际数据
the things that it that were
那是的东西
inconsistent as a result of my bug they
由于我的错误导致不一致
fixed themselves I didn't have to go and
修好自己，我不必走了，
write a database migration work out okay
写一个数据库迁移工作好了
which events didn't make it to the to
哪些事件并没有导致
the search service
搜索服务
do I need to republish them again they
我需要重新发布它们吗
that automatically happens because of
由于
this architectural approach that I've
我已经采用的这种架构方法
taken I'm able to take eventual
我能够接受
consistency for granted so using
一致性是理所当然的，因此使用
streaming you no longer need to worry
流媒体，您不再需要担心
about handling failure no longer need to
关于处理故障不再需要
worry about handling consistency
担心处理一致性
you
您
so in summary monoliths have allowed us
所以总的来说，巨石让我们
to take consistencies branded just the
采取一致性只是品牌
same way that we take oxygen for granted
我们认为氧气是理所当然的
we need consistency and they've let it
我们需要一致性，他们已经做到了
let us not worry about it but when we
让我们不用担心，但是当我们
move to cloud native micro services this
迁移到云原生微服务
consistent broke view of the world
一致的世界观
breaks down and what worked for us in
崩溃了，什么对我们有用
monoliths will not work in cloud native
独石将无法在云原生环境中工作
mario services if we model a system
mario服务（如果我们为系统建模）
using streams we embrace events ok our
使用流，我们接受事件
data becomes the events not not what's
数据成为事件不是不是什么
stored in the database is the current
当前存储在数据库中
state in the tables but the events
表中的状态，但事件
themselves they are our data be our
自己，他们是我们的数据，是我们的
source of truth they're what we can
真理之源就是我们所能
trust
信任
we no longer need a single state we
我们不再需要单一状态
don't need to also acid transactions to
不需要也将交易添加到
give us this illusion that there's
给我们这种错觉，
there's a current state that we can
有一个当前状态，我们可以
depend on and by doing that we can take
依靠并做到这一点，我们可以采取
eventual consistency for granted we have
最终的一致性理所当然
a system that self heals we don't need
一个自我修复的系统，我们不需要
to be coding in vitro logic rollback the
进行体外逻辑回滚编码
logic it's it's done for us
逻辑就是为我们完成了
automatically by the by virtue of the
凭借
architecture of using streams of this
使用此流的体系结构
constantly converging moving data in
不断汇聚移动数据
motion view of the world and I hope
我希望看到世界的运动
you've seen that Jack Jakarta is on
你已经看到杰克·雅加达
track to helping nutrients transition to
跟踪帮助营养物质过渡到
this new world
这个新世界
so thank you for listening
所以谢谢你的倾听
the the specs themselves are available
规格本身可用
on github so github calm equips micro
在github上，所以github冷静地装备了微
profile reactive please get involved if
个人资料反应性，请参与
you if you are interested in this at all
如果您对此完全感兴趣
even if you have never done anything to
即使您从未做过任何事情
do with reactive or messaging or events
处理反应性或消息传递或事件
before what we really need is people to
在我们真正需要的是人们之前
go and and ask the questions what does
去问问题是什么
that mean how does that actually work
那意味着它实际上是如何工作的
because it's an it's important that we
因为这对我们很重要
get validation from from people as to
得到人们的认可
whether this will actually work when it
当它实际是否有效
goes out into the real world we have a a
进入现实世界，我们有一个
weekly hangout that the time of it's
每周的视讯聚会时间
about to change but if you subscribe to
即将改变，但如果您订阅
micro profile list you'll find out what
微型个人资料列表，您会发现什么
the time of that is this actual
那是实际时间
demonstration that I've done you can
我已经做过的示范可以
find it at github comm / 0 / / streaming
在github comm上找到它/ 0 / /流式
- new - Jakarta AE if we want to just
-新-如果我们只想雅加达AE
play around with that demo app and if
玩这个演示应用程序，如果
you're interested in more about what
您对更多内容感兴趣
reactive streams can do for Jakarta AAA
反应流可用于雅加达AAA
there's a blog post that I published
我发表了一篇博客文章
about four or four months ago - probably
大约四四个月前-可能
the best thing to search for is James
最好的搜索是James
wrote the light then to extremes to
然后把光写到极端
Qatar AAA unless you can memorize that
卡塔尔AAA，除非您可以记住
address but it goes through a whole
地址，但它贯穿整个
broad range of specs and possibilities
广泛的规格和可能性
for for how streams can be embraced in
对于如何可以包含流
Jakarta AAA so thank you for listening
雅加达AAA，谢谢您的收听
any questions
任何问题
you
您
yep
是的
reactive strains itself is a
反应应变本身就是一个
specification for different streaming
不同流的规范
technologies to integrate with each
与每种技术集成的技术
other and that's definitely already
其他，那肯定已经
working in amalgam these annotations the
在这些汞合金中工作的注释
messaging spec that's I mean the codes
邮件规范，我的意思是代码
they're up on github but it's not
他们在github上，但不是
officially released it's and and it's
正式发布了
going to change like where these specs
这些规格会发生变化
specs are in process and in progress and
规范正在进行中，并且
and things about them will change
他们的事情将会改变
there's not even really a way yet to
甚至还没有真正的方法
confide to configure where your message
倾诉配置您的消息的位置
broker is and stuff like that so it's um
经纪人之类的东西，所以它是嗯
I'm hoping something will be that will
我希望会有所作为
be able to release of 100 by November
到11月能发行100张
this year for for the spec and there
今年的规格和那里
should be something corresponding
应该是对应的东西
running on lag on then
然后滞后
yep
是的
you
您
yep the question is how are the events
是的，问题是事件如何
stored in the in the bidding service
存储在招标服务中
with a yet so they are stored using
与一个，所以他们被存储使用
something called
被称为
ARCA persistence it supports multiple
ARCA持久性，它支持多个
backends in this case I'm using
在这种情况下，我正在使用后端
Cassandra and basically it's a table in
卡桑德拉，基本上是一张桌子
Cassandra and all the events are stored
Cassandra和所有事件均已存储
indexed both by the entity ID so that's
两者均由实体ID编制索引，因此
the auction ID so that you can replay
拍卖ID，以便您可以重播
the events for a single oxygen to get
单个氧气获取的事件
the state for that option as well as
该选项的状态以及
been indexed by the the offset of the
由的偏移量索引
event so they can then be published to
活动，然后可以将其发布到
the the message broker
消息代理